Guide to the Vassar College Subject Files, 1864–2023
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Subject Files
1864-2023
Vassar College
46 cubic feet, 1 box
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of materials documenting the history of Vassar College, collected by various departments of the Library over several decades. There are also some materials on Poughkeepsie, Dutchess County, the Hudson Valley, students in general, and other colleges.
Scope and Content Note
An artificial collection of materials documenting the history of Vassar College, collected by various departments of the Library over several decades. Included are minutes, reports, questionnaires, letters, publications, programs, speeches, autograph albums, handbooks, articles, clippings, bibliographies, curriculum materials, and other items concerning Vassar College alumnae, anniversaries, art exhibits, athletics, Black Studies, buildings, offices and departments, classes, clubs and organizations, community relations, conferences, deans, faculty, faculty committees, folklore, gardens, Jewish Studies, Library, presidents, religious life, students, trustees, World Wars I and II, and women. There are also some materials on Poughkeepsie, Dutchess County, the Hudson Valley, students in general, and other colleges. Organized by subject.
Access
Some materials relating to the "Vassar Veterans" is currently closed to research. The rest of this collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College. Jewish Studies; Vassar College. Black Studies; Vassar College. Library; Vassar College--Curricula; Vassar College--Religion; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College--Anniversaries, etc.; Vassar College--Athletics; Vassar College--Buildings; Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Presidents
Subjects:
Art--Exhibitions; Women--Education; Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Community and college--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Folklore; Gardens; Women--Societies and clubs; Blacks--Study and teaching; Judaism--Study and teaching; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945
Places:
Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--Description; Dutchess County (N.Y.)--Description and travel; Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.)--Description and travel
Document Types:
Autographs; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Newsletters; Pamphlets; Printed ephemera
VCL Categories:
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, May-June 2007.
Acquisition Information
An artificial collection, collected by various departments of the Library from multiple sources over several decades.
Container List
- Adelphi and Vassar (Folder 1.1)
- American Association of University Professor. Vassar Chapter (Folder 1.2-1.4)
- American Association of University Women (Folder 1.5-1.7)
- American Federation of Teachers (Folder 1.8)
- American Student Union. (Folder 1.9)
- American Student Union. Vassar Chapter (Folder 1.10)
- Arlington see also: V.C. Poughkeepsie, Relations with (Folder 1.11)
- A.S.I.A. Review (Folder 1.12)
- Associated Colleges of the Mid-Hudson Area (Folder 1.13-1.21)
- Association of Colleges and Universities in the State of New York (Folder 1.22)
- Association of Collegiate Alumnae, see: American Association of University Women
- Bardavon 1869 Opera House (Poughkeepsie) (Folder 1.23)
- Boots and Saddle Club (Folder 1.24)
- [EMPTY] (Folder 1.25)
- Coeducation 1968, see: V.C. Coeducation
- Cold Spring Institute and Cold Spring Project, see: Walt Foundation
- College and University Personnel Association. Eastern Region (Folder 1.26)
- College Center, see: Associated Colleges of the Mid-Hudson Area
- College Inn, see: Wagner Inn
- College Research Center (Folder 1.27)
- Community Chest, see also: Associated College of the Mid-Hudson Area (Folder 1.28)
- Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe, Inc. (CARE) (Folder 1.29)
- Cooperative Program for Educational Opportunity (Folder 1.30)
- Council for Financial Aid to Education (Folders 1.31-1.32)
- Dale-Lichtenstein Stamp Collection see: V.C. Gifts
- Daughters of the American Revolution. Poughkeepsie Chapter, see also: V.C. DAR Chapter (Folder 1.33)
- Dix Plan (Folder 1.34)
- Dutchess County Art Association (Folder 1.35)
- Dutchess County Arts Council, Inc. (Folder 1.36)
- Dutchess County Outdoor Ecological Laboratory (Folder 1.37)
- Dutchess County Social Planning Council (Folder 1.38)
- Dutchess County Society in the City of New York (Folder 1.39)
- Eastern Colleges Science Conference, 1947 (Folder 1.40)
- Economic History Association (Folder 1.41)
- Eight-college Conference, see also: Seven-college Conference, V.C. Five College Project, Twelve College Program (Folder 1.42)
- Elmira and Vassar (Folder 1.43)
- Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen (Folder 1.44)
- Empire State Foundation of Independent Liberal Arts Colleges, Inc. European Group (Folder 1.45)
- Flight, see: V.C. Group Travel (Folder)
- The Flag Shop (Folder 1.46)
- Evening Russian Program see: V.C. Evening Russian Program
- Fudge see: V.C. Fudge
- Girl Scouts (Folder 1.47)
- Grist (Folder 1.48)
- Horizons Unlimited (Folder 1.49)
- Hudson River Anthology (Folder 1.50)
- Hudson Valley Archaeological Survey (Folder 1.51)
- Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra (Folder 1.52)
- The Imperialist, see: V. C. Moderate, Independent and Conservative Alliance
- Institute for a Christian Basis of World Relations (Folder 1.52a)
- Institute for New York State High School Teachers of English (Folder 1.53)
- Intercollegiate Community Service Association (Folder 1.54)
- International Conference on World Education Problems (Folder 1.55)
- International Federation of University Women (Folder 1.56)
- International Summer School of the Nursery School Association of Great Britain (Folder 1.57)
- Lake Minnewaska, see: Lake Minnewaska in the Special Collections File
- Lake Mohonk, see: Lake Mohonk in the Special Collections File
- [EMPTY] (Folder 1.58)
- Lincoln Center (Poughkeepsie) (Folder 1.59)
- Lisburne Grange (Folder 1.60)
- Listening In, see: V.C. Associate Alumnae Publications
- Little Review (Folder 1.61)
- Marine Biological Laboratory (Wood's Hole, MA) (Folder 1.62)
- Marine Midland Bank of Southeastern New York (originally VassarBank), also called: Marine Midland Bank of Southern New York, Marine Midland National Bank (Folder 1.63)
- Mathematical refresher course for teachers (Folder 1.64)
- Middle East, Summer Seminar on the Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, see: V.C. Middle...
- Mid-Hudson Association of Colleges, see: Lake Minnewaska in the Special Collections File (Folder 1.65)
- Mid-Hudson Civic Center (Folder 1.66)
- Model Senate Association (Folder 1.67)
- Model United Nations General Assembly (Folder 1.68)
- Mount Holyoke and Vassar (Folder 1.69)
- Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, see: V.C. Lecturers and Visitors: Moynihan
- National Citizen's Political Action Committee. Vassar Chapter (Folder 1.70)
- National Council for Vassar College, 1980- (Folder 1.71)
- National Defense Student Loan Program (Folder 1.72)
- National Organization for Women (NOW). Vassar Chapter (Folder 1.73)
- National Student Federation of America (Folder 1.74)
- New York Public Interest Research Group. Vassar Branch (Folder 1.75)
- New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (Folder 1.76)
- New York State Citizen's Council, Inc. (Folder 1.77)
- Nobel Prize (Folder 1.78)
- "Peace I Leave With You" (Vassar Choir Song) (Folder 1.79)
- Physical Education (general) (Folder 1.80)
- Pike Controversy (Folder 1.80a)
- Poughkeepsie Ballet Theatre (Folder 1.81)
- Poughkeepsie College Center, see: Associated College of the Mid-Hudson Area
- Poughkeepsie Day School (Folder 1.82)
- Poughkeepsie Rural Cemetery (Folder 1.83)
- Present Tense (Folder 1.84)
- Raymond Avenue (Folder 1.85)
- Russian Program, see: V.C. Evening Russian Program
- S.S. Vassar Victory (Folder 1.86)
- Sarah Lawrence and Vassar (Folder 1.87)
- Schooner Matthew Vassar, Jr. (Folder 1.88)
- Seven-college Conference, see also: Eight-college Conference, Twelve-college Program, V.C. Endowment, Campaign of Seven Colleges, V.C. Five-college Project (Folder 2.1)
- Seven Colleges, Alumnae Committee of (Folder 2.2)
- Seven Colleges, Alumnae Committee of: annual reports and brochures, 1929-1939 (Folder 2.2a)
- Student Aid Society, see: Vassar Students Aid Society
- Student Christian Movement. Conference, 1949 (Folder 2.3)
- Summer Institute in Earth Science, see: Summer Institute in Geology
- Summer Institute in Geology, 1961-1970 (Folder 2.4)
- Summer Institute in the Fundamentals of Geology; Summer Institute in the Principles of Geology, see: Summer Institute in Geology, V.C. Summer Programs
- Summer Science Training Program in Chemistry (Folder 2.5)
- Summer Seminar on the Middle East, see: Middle East, Summer Seminar on...
- Symposium Committee of the 175th Anniversary of the New York State Ratification of the Federal Constitution (Folder 2.6)
- Taconic Art Center (Folder 2.7)
- Twelve-college Program (Folder 2.8)
- Union College and Vassar (Folder 2.9)
- United Way of Dutchess County, see also: Community Chest, V.C. Vassar Drive, War-chest of Greater Poughkeepsie (Folder 2.10)
- University Community Relations Project (Folder 2.11)
- Unscrewed (Folder 2.12)
- Urban Center for Black/Africana Studies (Folder 2.13)
- Urban Center for Black/Africana Studies Newsletter (Folder 2.14-2.16)
- Vague (Folder 2.17)
- Valley Vagabonds (Folder 2.18)
- Vassar College (Folder 2.19-2.21)
- Vassar Alumnae Historical Association (Folder 2.22)
- Vassar Alumnae Magazine, see also: Vassar Quarterly (Folder 2.23)
- Vassar Alumnae Monthly (Folder 2.24)
- Vassar Bank, see: Marine Midland Bank of Southeastern New York
- Vassar Brew (Folder 2.25)
- Vassar Bulletin and Vassar Daily (Folder 2.26)
- [EMPTY] (Folder 2.27)
- Vassar Chronicle (Folder 2.28)
- Vassar Club, see: V.C. Associate Alumnae. Branches
- Vassar Collage, see: V.C. Student Entertainment Committee
- V. C. Abbot Scholarship (Folder 2.29)
- V. C. Academic Computer Center (Folder 2.30)
- V. C. Academic Computing (Folder 2.31)
- V. C. Academic Freedom (Folder 2.32)
- V. C. Academic Processions (Folder 2.33)
- V. C. Academic Records and Research (Folder 2.34)
- V. C. Academic Resource Center (Folder 2.35)
- V. C. Acceleration, see also: V.C. Three-year plan (Folder 2.36)
- V. C. Administration (Folder 2.37)
- V. C. Administration, Vice-President for, see: V.C. President for Administration
- V. C. Admissions, Office of (for material beginning January 1970), see also: V.C. Faculty, Committees, Admission, Committee on (for materials through 1969) (Folder 2.38-2.39)
- V. C. Advertisements (Folder 2.40)
- V. C. Advisory System (Folder 2.41)
- V. C. Affirmative Action (Folder 2.42)
- V. C. Africana Studies, see: V.C. Departments. Africana Studies
- V. C. Alcohol Task Force, see: V.C. Drug and Alcohol Task Force
- V.C. All College Assembly, Feb. 2 1983 (Folder 2.43)
- V. C. Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College see also: V.C. Associate Alumnae and the following sub-headings for earlier materials (Folder 2.44)
- V. C. Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College. Annual Report (corrections and additions) (Folder 2.45)
- V. C. Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College. Black Alumnae/i Forum, 1984- (Folder 2.46)
- V. C. Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College. News From Across the Street (Folder 2.47)
- V. C. Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College. Seminars and Conferences. (Folder 2.48)
- V. C. Alumnae Fund, see: V.C. Associate Alumnae, Alumnae Fund
- V. C. Alumnae House (Folder 2.49-2.51)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Calendar (Folder 2.53)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Dependent child, 1925 (Folder 2.54)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Eclipse of the sun, 1925 (Folder 2.55)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. First Educational, 1924 (Folder 2.56)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Educational, 1925 (Folder 2.57)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Educational, 1927- (Folder 2.58)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Garden, 1925, 1932 (Folder 2.59)
- V .C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Journalism, 1925 (Folder 2.60)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Miscellaneous and General, 1925- (Folder 2.61-2.62)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Conferences. Modern Novel (Wylie), 1925 (Folder 2.63)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Library (Folder 2.64)
- V. C. Alumnae House, Pub (Folder 2.52)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, (general) (Folder 2.65-2.66)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Authors (Folder 2.67-2.68)
- V. C. Alumnae/,i Authors, children's books (Folder 2.69)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Authors, Marked class list from Alumnae Register (Folder 2.70)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Authors, unidentified (Folder 2.71)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Degrees (Folder 2.72)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Distinguished (Folder 2.73-2.74)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Lesbian and Gay, see: V.C. LAGA-VC
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Local (Folder 2.75)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Statistics, Vital (Folder 2.76-2.77)
- V. C. Alumnae/i, Vocations (Folder 2.78)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in advertising (Folder 2.79)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in agriculture, ecology and conservation (Folder 2.80)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in anthropology (Folder 2.81)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in archaeology (Folder 2.82)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in architecture (Folder 2.83)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in art (Folder 2.84)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in book-arts (publishing, book-selling, printing, etc) (Folder 2.85)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in business (Folder 2.86)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in community affairs (Poughkeepsie area only) (Folder 2.87)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in city planning, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in urban and area planning
- V. C. Alumnae/i in dance (Folder 2.88)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in diplomatic service (Folder 2.89)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in dramatic work (Folder 2.90)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in ecology and conservation, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in agriculture, ecology and conservation
- V. C. Alumnae/i in economics (Folder 2.91)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in education (Folder 3.1)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in engineering (Folder 3.2)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in government (Folder 3.3)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in graduate work (Folder 3.4)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in historical research, et. (Folder 3.5)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in homemaking (Folder 3.6)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in interior design (Folder 3.7)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in journalism, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in newspaper work
- V. C. Alumnae/i in law (Folder 3.8)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in library service (Folder 3.9)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in mathematics (Folder 3.10)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in medicine and related fields (including counseling) (Folder 3.11)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in military service (Folder 3.12)
- V.C. Alumnae/i in music (Folder 3.13)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in newspaper work (Folder 3.14)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in nursing, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in medicine and related fields
- V. C. Alumnae/i in Peace Corps (Folder 3.15)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in philanthropy (Folder 3.15a)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in physics, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in science
- V. C. Alumnae/i in political activities (Folder 3.16)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in public relations (Folder 3.17)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in radio and television (Folder 3.18)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in real estate (Folder 3.19)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in religion (Folder 3.20)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in science (Folder 3.21)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in secretarial work (Folder 3.22)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in social work (Folder 3.23)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in TV, see: V.C. Alumnae/i in radio and television
- V. C. Alumnae/i in the United Nations (Folder 3.24)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in urban and area planning (Folder 3.25)
- V. C. Alumnae/i in war service (both military and civilian) (Folder 3.26)
- V. C. Alumnae/i trustees (Folder 3.27)
- V. C. Amnesty International, Vassar Chapter (Folder 3.28)
- V. C. Anecdotes, see: V.C. Humor, caricatures, etc.
- V. C. Anniversaries. 10th (Folder 3.29)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 25th (Folder 3.30)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 50th. General (Folder 3.31-3.33)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 50th. News Clippings (Folder 3.34)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 50th. Programs (Folder 3.35-3.37)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 50th. Scrapbook (Folder 3.38)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 60th (Folder 3.39)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th (Folder 3.40-3.45)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Fund (Folder 3.46-3.47)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Gadgets (Folder 3.48)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Press bulletins (Folder 3.49)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Program (Folder 3.50)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Publications (Folder 3.51-3.52)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Publications, estimates (Folder 3.53-3.54)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Publications, reviews of (Folder 3.55)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 75th. Publicity (Folder 3.56)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 100th (Folder 3.57-3.62)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 100th. General (Folder 3.63)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 100th. International conference (Folder 3.64)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 100th. International conference (Folder 4.1-4.2)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 100th. Press releases. (Folder 4.3-4.4)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 125th. Press releases (Folder 4.5)
- V. C. Anniversaries. 150th (Folder 4.6)
- V. C. Annuity plan (Folder 4.7-4.8)
- V. C. Archaeology, Summer field work in (Folder 4.9)
- V. C. Architecture, see also: V.C. Buildings (Folder 4.10)
- V. C. Ars Pictoria, see also: V.C. Art Club (Folder 4.11)
- V. C. Art, School of (Folder 4.12)
- V. C. Art Club, see also: V.C. Ars Pictoria (Folder 4.13)
- V. C. Art Collections (Folder 4.14)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, undated to 1940 (Folder 4.15)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, 1941-1962 (Folder 4.16)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, 1963-1969 (Folder 4.17)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, 1970-1972 (Folder 4.18)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, 1973-1979 (Folder 4.19-4.21)
- V. C. Art Exhibitions, 1980- (Folder 4.22)
- V. C. Art Gallery, see also: V.C. Loeb Art Center (Folder 4.23-4.25)
- V. C. Asia View (Folder 4.26)
- V. C. Asian Students Association, see also: V.C. Association of Students interested in Asia 1981 (Folder 4.27)
- V. C. Asian Students' Association, Bamboo Stand (Folder 4.28)
- V. C. Asian Studies Program (Folder 4.29)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae (general) (Folder 4.30-4.33)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Alumnae Fund (Folder 4.34-4.36)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Annual and semi-annual meetings (Folder 4.37-4.38)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Biographical records (Folder 4.39)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Board members (Folder 4.40)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches (general) (Folder 4.41)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Albany, N.Y. (Folder 4.42)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Boston (Folder 4.43)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Brooklyn (Folder 4.44)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Central and Western New York (Folder 4.45)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Chicago and the West (Folder 4.46)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Cincinnati (Folder 4.47)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Cleveland (Folder 4.48)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Fall River, MA (Folder 4.49)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Florida (Folder 4.50)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Grand Rapids, Michigan (Folder 4.51)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Indiana (Folder 4.52)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Kansas City (Folder 4.53)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. London (Folder 4.54)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Maryland (Folder 4.55)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. New Haven (Folder 4.56)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. New York City (Folder 5.1-5.3)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. New York City Opera (benefit) (Folder 5.4-5.5)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Oregon (Folder 5.6)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Philadelphia (Folder 5.7)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Pittsburgh (Folder 5.8)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Poughkeepsie (Folder 5.9)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Puget Sound (Folder 5.10)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Rochester (Folder 5.11)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. San Francisco (Folder 5.12)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. South-Eastern (Folder 5.13)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Southern California (Folder 5.14)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Virginia (Folder 5.15)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Washington, D. C. (Folder 5.16)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Westchester County, N. Y. (Folder 5.17)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Branches. Western New York (Folder 5.18)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Centennial, 1971 (Folder 5.19)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Committee on The Historical Museum (Folder 5.20)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Constitution and by-laws (Folder 5.21)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council (general) (Folder 5.22)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Adelaide Underhill's file (Folder 5.23)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Meetings, through 1939 (Folder 5.24)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Meetings, 1940-1959 (Folder 5.25)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Meetings, 1960-1979 (Folder 5.26)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Meetings, 1980- (Folder 5.27)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Council. Reports (Folder 5.28)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Endowment Fund Committee (Folder 5.29)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Fellowship (Folder 5.30)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Fiftieth Anniversary (Folder 5.31-5.32)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Graduate work and Publications, Sub Committee on (Folder 5.33)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Letters (Howland) (Folder 5.34)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Memorial Gift Book, see: V. C. Memorial Gift Book
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Post-commencement forum, see: V. C. Classroom '63
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Publications (Folder 5.35)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Publications. Listening In (Folder 5.36)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Questionnaires (Folder 5.37)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reading Lists (Folder 5.38)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Registers (Folder 5.39)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions (general and undated) (Folder 5.40)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1880-1949 (Folder 6.1)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1950-1969 (Folder 6.2)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1970-1979 (Folder 6.3)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1980 (Folder 6.4)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1981 (Folder 6.5)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1982-1989 (Folder 6.6)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Reunions, 1990- (Folder 6.7)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Scholarship Fund (Folder 6.8)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Secretary (Folder 6.9)
- V. C. Associate Alumnae. Vassar Alumnae War Service Fund (Folder 6.10)
- V. C. Associate Fellows (Folder 6.11)
- V. C. Association for the Handicapped (Folder 6.12)
- V. C. Association of Students interested in Asia, see also: V. C. Asian Students Association for material before 1981 (Folder 6.13)
- V. C. Athletic Association (Folder 6.14)
- V. C. Athletic Field, see: V. C. Prentiss Field
- V. C. Athletics, see: V. C. Students, Athletics
- V. C. Audio-visual Center, see also: V. C. Libraries. Media Resources (Folder 6.15)
- V.C. Auditorium seating chart (Folder 6.16)
- V. C. Auditor's reports (Folder 6.17)
- V. C. Aula, see: V. C. Buildings. Ely
- V. C. Avery Theater (Folder 6.18)
- V. C. Awards (to) (Folder 6.19)
- EMPTY (Folders 6.20-6.21)
- V. C. Baccalaureate Services - See: Vassar College Baccalaureate and Commencement Records
- V. C. Band (Folder 6.22)
- V. C. Barbara Bailey Brown Lecture Series, 1966- (Folder 6.23)
- V. C. Bequests see: V. C. Gifts and bequests
- V. C. Bibliography (Folder 6.24)
- V. C. Bicycles (Folder 6.25)
- V. C. Bill of Rights (Folder 6.26)
- V. C. Bird Bath (Folder 6.27)
- V. C. Bisexual, Gay and Lesbian Alliance (BiGALA) (Folder 6.27A)
- V. C. Black-out (Folder 6.28)
- V. C. Black Students Union (Folder 6.29)
- V. C. Black Studies, see: V. C. Departments. Africana Studies, V. C. Departments. Black Studies
- V. C. Blakeley Prize (Folder 6.30)